# Sadeq Basel Jallad Curriculum Vitae

# **Construction Manager**

Address: UAE-DUBAI

E-mail: sadeq.jallad@gmail.com

Mobile: +971559545833- UAE

Date of Birth: 03. July.1985

Nationality: Jordanian Marital Status: Married

### **CAREER OVERVIEW**

With 15 years of experience in Construction field, I bring expertise in Construction management, Real stat Construction and Development. During my time in Construction Field, I have successfully completed Development of Large Real estate Projects with well known Developers in the market such as Nakheel, Wasl and Dubai Properties. My background in Civil Engineering, Construction Management and PMC has equipped me with the necessary knowledge and expertise to excel in the role of Construction Manager.

## **EDUCATION**

#### 2004-2009

B.Sc. in Civil Engineering (Construction) from Misr University for Science & Technology, (Cairo-Egypt) with total assignment Good.

## **LANGUAGES**

- Arabic: Mother language.
- English: Excellent in reading, writing and speaking.

# **EXPERIENCE**

July 2024 - Present

AL SAHEL CONTRACTING COMPANY

Beach gate by address, Dubai, UAE (Residential Building Project)

Developer: Emaar Construction Manager



Tower (Ground floor+ 7 Podium +35 Typical Floors)

November 2021 – July 2024 TURNER CONSTRUCTION INTERNATIONAL Mohamed Bin Rashed Al Maktoum City, Dubai, UAE (Residential Building Project)

Developer: Nakheel Construction Manager



Development for District One Phase 3A Residences consists of apartment buildings which are designed to face the Crystal Lagoon waterfront destination for the public while offering affordable waterfront living, on a land area of 1,068,752 Sqm. and GFA of 555,000 Sqm. The development is divided into three smaller subphases of Phase 3A.1, 3A.2 & 3A.3 each consists of various types of residential apartments construction as well as related infrastructure works, Crystal Lagoon and Landscape Parks.

# Sadeq Basel Jallad Curriculum Vitae

July 2018 – November 2021 SSANGYONG ENGINEERING & CONSTRUCTION CO.

AL-Kifaf Development, Dubai, UAE (Residential Building Project)

Developer: Wasl
Civil-Project Engineer



2 Towers (3 Basement + Ground floor+ 4 Podium +42Typical Floors)

September 2017- July 2018

<u>DELTA EMIRATES CONTRACTING CO.</u>

Remraam Housing Community, Dubai, UAE (Residential Building Project)

Developer: Dubai Properties

<u>Civil-Project Engineer</u>



3 Clusters, 2 Buildings each cluster (Ground floor + Podium + 6 Typical Floors)

October 2015- September 2017

GHANTOOT GENERAL CONTRACTING CO.

Abu Dhabi Trade Center PH.3, Abu Dhabi, UAE
(Residential Building Project)

Civil-Project Engineer



2 Towers (4 Basement + Ground Floor+ 3 Podiums + 25 Typical Floors)

October 2014- October 2015

AMANA CONTRACTING CO.

Dubai Design District, Dubai, UAE (Commercial Building Project)



Tower (2Basement+Ground Floor+ 13 Typical Floors)

October 2012- October 2014

<u>ALFARAA GENERAL CONTRACTING CO.</u>

Sheikh Khalifa Medical City/Dialysis Center,
Abu dhabi, UAE.
Civil Site Engineer



(Basement + Ground Floor + First Floor + Roof)

# Sadeq Basel Jallad Curriculum Vitae

# September 2009- October 2012 ORIENT HOUSE CONSTRUCTION CO. Civil Site Engineer

Project 1: Precast Staff Accommodation, Abu Dhabi, UAE.

(8 Buildings G+3, Kitchen Block G+2, Laundry, Mosque, Library).

Project 2: Industrial complex, Abu Dhabi, UAE. (17 ware houses)

#### Roles & Responsibilities

- Daily monitoring of field progress works and site follow up.
- Assist the Main Contractor in the Logistical planning, considering that the relevant infrastructure works are going in parallel to buildings works, the same is required to maintain the smooth flow of the construction activities in this widely spread project. Oversee and review the operations of the PCS team in the implementation of tracking, logging, expediting, and monitoring systems, and the preparation of associated periodic status reports.
- Oversee and review the consultant payment certificate of the contractor's work valued in accordance with project progress.
- Oversee and review Extension of time and Variations.
- Ensuring Project Consultant approvals on Main Contractor Submittals and Transmittals are in line with project specifications and authorities' regulations as per clint's requirements.
- Assist with preparation of reports that was
- Optimizes manpower productivity, equipment, and materials allocation, and ensures no materials are wasted on assigned part of project.
- Assigns responsibilities to on-site staff as per directions of Project Management.
- Implements the safety requirements in coordination with Safety Officer.
- Supervises staff and non –staff attendance and productivity.
- Interfaces/coordinates with sub-contractors to ensure compliance of project implementation with construction schedule.
- Assists with preparation of construction schedule, manpower histogram, submittal log, and drawing log, and any changes thereof, in coordination with Construction staff and

- Planning& Cost Control Units for initial project planning.
- Assists with preparation of ahead schedules for project implementation.
- Coordinates with Project Manager on preparation of all project submittals and drawings.
- Interfaces/follows up with suppliers to verify materials received.
- Oversees purchase and delivery of required materials, and inflow/outflow of site store materials in coordination with Procurement Department.
- Organizing weekly meetings with Project Manager, and Site Engineer(s) for look-a head plan.
- Interfaces/interacts and coordinate with consultants.
- Coordinates with technical team against any shop drawings preparations.
- Pre approvals on Inspection Request raised by site team to the QA/QC team.
- Reviews the Variations / Change Orders / Time extensions with the Project Manager to give feedback about the impact on the project.
- Assists in the preparation of the project close out reports
- Assists in the training and development of personnel in the Construction function.

### **SKILLS & EFFICIENCIES**

- Strong leadership and motivational skills.
- Organizational knowledge.
- Problem-solving and resource planning skills.
- Creating project reports.
- Managing and prioritizing tasks.
- Verbal and written communication skills.
- Computer Literate Microsoft office (Word, Excel &Power point)
- Course in PMP
- Valid UAE driving License.